[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Good evening. Good day everybody and
welcome to this special emergency
episode of the Ask Abijit show. Uh we
are talking about the fact that we are a
nation at war. You know wars don't have
to be declared. You are at war. We are
at war. India is currently now at war
with Pakistan. It's not a war that's
been declared but there's action
happening as we speak right now.
Pakistanis are trying to uh target
Indian cities along our western border
with drone and missile strikes right now
and we are u intercepting those u
attempts and I'm I suppose we'll be
retaliating in some manner. So we are we
are in a state of war right now. Uh and
that's what we're going to discuss
today. So it all started a couple of
days ago uh with uh India responding to
the Pakistani massacre of of civilians
in Jammu and Kashmir in Palgam and it
was for Pakistan to just accept the fact
that they they had done this terrible
thing and they should uh absorb uh the
Indian punishment but they decided to
strike try and strike back and so on. So
we're going to discuss that today but
before we get into that let's see who
all is there on the live live chat. I
can see Bhavan Trading Grow Sri Ram
Chandra Nahab Gorov Duv Kumar DK Anand
Pay Kesha Chawan Goresh KB Airal Gandhi
Vidang Mishra Manendraal 234 Jay Kumar
Ara Manat Arnaviagi Krishna Raun from
the Suriname Netherlands Amisha Mishra
HLWFPS Angad Singh Samritig Swami Sham
Shawantra Vikram Gorav Jagdish Mali
Rashmi Ratur Lakshi Bhutak Sange
Chim Dongar Singh, Johan, Madhav, Durve,
U and and so many other people. I can
see PR Remy Dip uh inner satisfaction
Alvin Rodriguez and lots of other
people. I won't be able to greet you all
other ones. I'll do that all day, but
let's get into the questions that you
all have asked. We've asked a lot of
questions. I'm going to take questions
from uh the questions you've asked in
the uh comments. So, let's get into it.
What's question one? Willie John says,
"Can you agree to the fact that war
always leads to suffering and pain?
Looking back at every war, every victims
of the war wishes it doesn't ever it did
not ever happen." I, you know, if you
want to do a root cause analysis of what
causes suffering and pain, then it is
incorrect to say that war causes
suffering and pain. It's not war that
causes suffering and pain. It is evil
people and evil ideas and evil
ideologies and so on that causes
suffering and pain. And when you have
evil people imposing suffering and pain
on their victims, the victims have a
choice. Either we suffer, we accept this
suffering and pain or we give it back to
the evil people. Right? So we have two
choices as as the victims. We either
suffer ourselves or we respond and give
it back to the evil people. And the
solution if you want to end suffering
and pain, it is to end these evil people
and ideas. That is the solution. War is
not the problem. There can be just
causes for war. Please understand that
there are just and righteous causes for
war at times.
So it is not war that's the root cause
of suffering and pain. It is evil people
and evil ideas that are the root cause
of suffering and pain. And those have to
be ended. And India has made a choice.
We will no longer sit back and take it.
We're going to begin the process of
dismantling and ending the evil people
and the evil
ideas that reside within this artificial
temporary nation called Pakistan.
Prane Paul says what's your overall
assessment of operation Synindur thus
far based on what we have seen in the
public domain in the backdrop of the
brutal Pahalgam attack and decades of
hostility with this temporarily carved
out nation radical nation how
significant is this operation
strategically and symbolically do you
think Pakistan is feeling the heat
beyond just physical strikes perhaps
diplomatically psychologically and
economically how squeezed are they
really and where could this be heading
in the coming weeks and months Is
operation Synindur even concluded yet or
are we just getting started? Operation
Synindur is continuing right now. It was
supposed it should have been a one-off
thing, you know, uh India hits at these
Pakistani terrorist uh infrastructure,
the terror camps and so on and that
should be that should have been the end
of it. But the Pakistani military gave
to chose to give the terrorists state
funerals. They chose to mingle their
army officers with the terrorists and
then they chose to try and hit more than
15 Indian cities last night. All their
attempts were intercepted. All their
missiles and drones were intercepted and
then today responded by hitting multiple
targets, military targets within
Pakistan in various Pakistani cities,
Lahar, Karachi and whatnot. Uh so I
think it's an ongoing thing operation.
My overall assessment so far is that
Pakistan has been
humiliated and I don't say say this with
a great amount of joy or anything. They
deserve
it. This nation has has been under the
impression for decades that they can act
with impunity and they can keep bleeding
India with a with a strategy of a
thousand cuts. Well, it's not going to
happen anymore and India will no longer
be willing to offer Pakistan a face
saver. We slap you, you slap us back and
then we end. No, we slapped you because
we are right. You try to slap us back,
we're going to stop the slap and we're
going to slap you back twice as hard.
And this will not end as long as
Pakistan doesn't try to keep
retaliating. They need to sit
down. That's what needs to happen. And
they then need to dismantle their
terrorist
infrastructure and all this needs to be
proven. Then India will um decide
whether to stop operation Synindur or
not. And as long as Pakistan tries to
retaliate or escalate, we will
respond in a proportionate manner and
we'll keep responding in a pro
proportionate manner. And Pakistan
cannot afford a long drawn out situation
such as this. They cannot afford to make
this the new normal. Every night you're
going you're going to have skirmishes
and artillery fire on civilians and and
drones and missiles targeted Indian
Indian cities. They simply don't have
the resources to sustain this to
continue this. They are a nation that is
on the brink of this perpetually on the
brink of bankruptcy. They can't sustain
this. So uh it's a dangerous situation
that Pakistan uh is dragging itself
into. Uh Pakistan is feeling the heat
very much. They are humiliated. Their
armed forces are humiliated. Their
civilians can see that uh they don't
have any air defenses. It's very clear
India is striking at will at the in the
heart of Pakistan. Not not 50 kilome 50
km from the border but all the way
wherever we want. Karachi, Islamabad,
Raal Pindi, wherever.
So the people of Pakistan can see that
the military which
um draws its legitimacy from painting
India as the as the as the as the uh
danger to Pakistan as an exist
existential threat and the military that
draws its legitimacy from their claim
that they can protect Pakistan against
India. Well, their claims are clearly
hollow. Um and if this continues, the
people of Pakistan will rebel against
the military dictatorship. Uh so
Pakistan is feeling the heat.
Economically they they are in in
terrible shape. Uh psychologically uh
it's it's terrible for the morale of a
nation when this happens when when their
adversity can strike them at will at the
the in the heart of the country. So it's
terrible psychologically and psych and
for the morale of of the nation. And
diplomatically look
uh I think China will stand with
Pakistan. The US will not feel that this
is a good time to stand with Pakistan
considering everything that's happened
and everything that Pakistan stands for.
So Pakistan is let's what's the cricket
term? It's on a sticky
wicket. Mazar Chachar says can you
provide details about uh the types of
drones used by India in today's incident
involved in Pakistan. The local media
here in Pakistan is reporting that 25
Indian drones were intercepted and
downed. Were these drones suicide or
kamikaza drones or of a different kind?
So we have a viewer from Pakistan. He's
a longtime viewer and I feel I feel
terrible that we are in this situation.
You see there are good people in
Pakistan. No question about it. And and
you know what? I I have absolutely
nothing against the ordinary people of
Pakistan. But they are citizens of a
nation that stands for terrorism. What
can I do? It's it's terrible. That's the
the cost that the people of Pakistan are
sadly having to pay for the misdeeds of
the dictatorship, the military
dictatorship, the ISI military terrorist
combination entity that is holding
Pakistan hostage. Anyhow, to answer your
question, Mazer, um the only drone that
that is confirmed to have been used is
the Harop drone. It's an Israeli
designed drone that's manufactured in
apparently in very large numbers in
India. And these are drones that have a
long endurance. They can loiter for
several hours before descending on their
target. These are subsonic drones, not
supersonic drones. They travel at they
fly at less than the speed of sound and
they can loiter, like I said, for for
several hours. And while loitering over
an area, they can um uh they can ingest
and transmit valuable intelligence about
what they are seeing. So they are
reconnaissance drones but they also
eventually at the end of their mission
turn into suicide or kamikaz drones and
they they carry an explosive uh uh
payload which is delivered to the place
where the drone eventually ends up
striking. So that's the Israeli designed
har drone that's made in India and they
produce this screaming sound apparently
that when they when they descend on the
target target apparently that's what one
hears. uh and these are known to have
been used today. There is footage on
social media from within Pakistan of
people Pakistani people you know filming
the drone descending and slamming into
the target. Um and u look the Pakistani
media and and the armed forces the
military Pakistani military is reporting
that multiple 25 Indian drones were
intercepted or whatever but uh okay I
don't know how many drones were fired by
India but we know that there have been
multiple hits on Pakistani targets and
those are known those are corroborated
from so many citizens who who have
filmed this and put put on social media
some of that has been captured live the
drones striking you know so uh there
obviously have been multiple hits and
that too in the heart of Pakistan and on
on military installations in various
Pakistani cities including Lahore near
the airport I believe in Rahindi some
place Karachi as well and so on u so
it's possible that other types of drones
may also have been involved uh the first
night of operation Synindur we know that
multiple hits were done multiple strikes
were done by India on multiple locations
so one location would be struck three,
four, five times to ensure its
destruction and the elimination of all
terrorist human beings inside. And these
strikes were recorded, they were filmed
by Indian drones and those films were
put out as evidence by the government of
India in that first press conference. So
you can see that the Indian loitering
drone which is a slowmoving drone is is
loitering over the target and it is
filming. You can see the bomb is
descending or the or the yeah the
payload is descending on the target and
then then the target target blows up. So
you have Indian drones over Pakistani
territory loitering and filming this
calmly while it happens and these
slowmoving drones were not taken out by
the Pakistani air defenses which kind of
raises enormous questions over the uh
quality of the Pakistani air defense. I
can understand if they can't take out
Abraham's missile because it's it
travels too fast. But you have these
slowmoving drones that they should be
able to take out but they have not been
able to. So how did India manage this is
the question. Did we use electronic
counter measures? Did we use harm or arm
missiles of some kind? Anti-radiation
missiles what is it? I think it's not
going to come out for a long time what
India did and how it has been done. But
please understand this is an ongoing
process. The action is happening right
now as we
speak. Pranay Paul says based on
confirmed details in the public domain
from the first round of operation sindur
including precision strikes on terror
camps and the elimination of key
individuals linked even to the horror
even to horrors like 261 the Mumbai
attacks. Would you assess this as a
decisive and significant blow to
Pakistan's terror infrastructure? With
such deeprooted assets, many propped up
for decades by the West now being
dismantled by the Indian army. Do you
believe Pakistan will have the capacity
to rebuild these terror hubs again? Or
are we finally witnessing a long overdue
mission to permanently this
terrorist ecosystem? What's your
assessment of the scale and strategic
impact of the damage inflicted in this
phase?
Um look the damage inflicted in this
phase is not insignificant. Uh some of
the I think the headquarters of one of
the terrorist organizations Lashkar a
toy Toy toba le has been obliterated. Uh
what is it? Some some I don't know what
the name is I don't understand these
names in a foreign language. So
whatever. So the headquarters has been
obliterated and many terrorist uh uh
much significant ter terrorist
infrastructure has been destroyed and
you could you it's very clear that lots
of terrorists have died and they were g
given yesterday or whenever it was state
funerals by the Pakistani military. So
there and and and apparently a whole
large number of rel relatives of the of
one of the senior most terrorists Masoud
Azar right a large number of his
relatives were apparently killed uh in
the this one of the strikes including
his brother who apparently was was
linked was was connected with the with
the murder abduction and murder of
Daniel Pearl an American Jewish
journalist more than I think 25 26 years
ago in Pakistan. So we have brought we
have delivered justice to Daniel Pearl's
family. You see um so it is it is uh
what's happening what's happened thus
far is significant. I would not call it
a decisive blow that will permanently
Pakistan's terror
infrastructure. Uh but it is a huge uh
step in that direction and it is a
terrible blow to the morale of Pakistan.
Now they will feel that India can strike
them at will strike them anywhere within
Pakistan. That is very much clear now to
any terrorist any Pakistani terrorist
and from the fact that nobody has
supported Pakistan except for China
neither Iran neither Afghanistan neither
the Taliban Pakistan or whoever no one
has supported Pakistan in in what's
happened that that is going to you know
it hurts it's going to hurt if you if
you are a Pakistani terrorist or or a
member of the Pakistani establishment so
they're kind of isolated said the only
people standing with them are
essentially the Chinese and so on. Uh so
we haven't really dismantled the entire
terrorist infrastructure. We have
destroyed one of the headquarters of the
le and we have struck blows at the heart
of the terrorist establishment and uh so
it's it's a significant strike. It's
kind of an inflection point. Pakistan
will never look at India the same way
again. Until now Pakistan has looked at
looked upon India as a as a soft state
as a punching bag. You can keep on
jabbing at India and India will keep on
taking it. We gave them this
reinforcement learning over decades that
you can keep jabbing at India, keep
striking India, keep keep bleeding India
with a thousand cuts and India won't
respond. We gave them this reinforcement
learning. Well, now we are making them
unlearn them unlearn that. Now India is
not going to be a predictable nation. We
are not predictable anymore when it
comes to the waters of the
Indust region. the the six rivers of the
region and we are no longer going to be
predictable when it comes to uh our
military activities and military actions
against Pakistan. So yes, it's it's long
overdue and uh one hopes that this uh
has the eventual result of permanently
crippling and dismantling the terrorist
infrastructure of Pakistan which will be
a huge relief not just for the people of
Pakistan, the innocent civilians of
Pakistan but for the people of the
entire region of the entire subcontinent
and beyond. I mean Iran is not part of
the subcontinent. It will be a relief
from for them as well. Uh so it's a good
start. I will say it's a huge blow to
the morale and self-belief of the ISI
military terrorist entity which is one
and the same. It's all interchangeable.
An entity with a thousand faces. It's a
huge blow to their self-belief, their
morale. And now they're going to be
really fearful of India. And their
nuclear bluff has been called. Oh, we
have nuclear weapons. You touch us,
we're going to blow you up. Come on,
blow us up. What happened? what happened
to your nukes? You see, it's not that
easy. So, yeah, it's it's a significant
um it's it's it's definitely long
overdue and it's a huge change in the
way India
operates. Prrenipal again says many good
questions from Prayal. Brenal says what
with the confirmed elimination of Abdul
Rahul Azar the mastermind of the IC814
hijacking the air the Indian airlines
hijacking in in 1999 I believe it was in
operation Sundur how significant is this
milestone in Barat's counterterror
doctrine does this mark a strategic
shift from the reactive posturing to
surgical intelligence-driven
elimination of high value targets deep
within enemy territory. Is Operation
Sindor setting a new benchmark for
effectiveness in India's fight against
decades long, decades old terror
networks. I think it's a start. So yeah,
like I said, this guy Abd Abdul Rahul
Azar, I'm sorry, it's a foreign name. I
don't I can't pronounce it well, but he
was the brother of the other fellow
Masud Azar. And he this Abdul fellow was
apparently involved in the hij in the um
in the uh kidnapping and and murder of
Daniel Pearl, the American journalist.
And he was apparently also the
mastermind of the uh Indian Airlines
hijacking which started from Kathmandu
went through it. It happened in Amritsar
as well. The plane touched down and then
it went all the way to Kandahar and
Walthan and India ended up releasing
five dreaded terrorists in exchange for
the lives of whoever uh the prison the
the the passengers were on the plane. A
couple of them were killed I believe. Uh
anyhow so this individual this this
dreaded senior terrorist is now
confirmed to have been eliminated in
operation. Significant milestone for
sure. It has uh delivered justice to the
family of Daniel Pearl. It has also
delivered justice to the people to the
families of the people affected by the
Indian Airlines 81 flight 814 hijacking
which happened all those years ago and
it's going to be a significant milestone
in Barrett's counterterror doctrine if
we continue the same thing and I think
it's going to be continued now. Now
India will no longer play by the old
playbook of sitting back and absorbing
all the blows. We're going to give it
back and give it back twice as hard. So
if that continues if if that policy
continues from India's perspective from
from India then it's going to be a
significant milestone an inflection
point a tipping point in Parat's
counterterror doctrine and we're going
to play from a whole different playbook
uh going forward. So it is definitely an
inflection point and we're going to see
a whole different beast in India going
forward. That's what it looks like and
that I think is really
welcome. Okay, next question is by
peace. Why did we use aircraft to carry
out the precision strikes instead of
long range missiles which could have
been launched from our side without
getting inside enemy lines? Look
um our armed forces and our government
have given no details about how these
strikes were launched on Pakistani
targets. from the video evidence that
has been released which is unmistakably
of those Pakistani terror hubs within
Pakistan. No doubt about it. So the
video evidence shows bombs being dropped
from
drones and some other footage shows
other kinds of uh payloads being
delivered. Some of these could be smart
bombs. Some of these could be cruise
missiles. We are not 100% sure uh what
was the delivery mechanism. Uh there
have been certain foreign YouTube
channels that have speculated that uh it
was a combination of Indian Rafals and
Indian Sukhoy30s that was used to uh
launch the cruise missiles. There's
speculation that scalp missiles were
used that that Brahos supersonic
missiles were used and various spice
bombs were used and so on. Look, we
haven't given any details. All of this
is speculation. It's possible that most
of these uh payloads were were delivered
by missiles that were launched from the
ground. It's possible. It's possible.
It's also possible that they were
launched from aircraft. That's also
within the realm of possibility. But we
don't know for sure which uh modality
was used to deliver the these strikes.
So in case we used aircraft, let's say
in case we use aircraft, then there was
no need for us for crossing the line of
control or the international border. uh
we have missiles whether it's the
Brahmos missile or the whichever missile
the scalp missile whatever that's used
from with the Rafal there's no need to
cross the international border by by air
there's no need for the aircraft that
will launch the missiles to cross the
international border we the aircraft can
deliver those missiles to their
destinations from long distances from
standoff distances from 150 or 200 km
away so in case we used aircraft I can
assure you that those aircraft did not
cross the international border or the
line of control. But there is
no there's there is no way of knowing
thus far. There's no confirmation or
denial that we used aircraft. It's
possible that some aircraft were used
but we don't have the knowledge. Right?
So let's not assume that a we used
aircraft and b if we used the aircraft
then those aircraft crossed the LOC or
the international border. There's no
confirmation or denial of these things.
Chiraasti says after Pakistan's rocket
attacks on Indian cities on May 7, 2025,
India's morning drone strikes on May 8
today penetrated Chinese HQ9 and HQ16
air defenses targeting Pakistani
military hubs in Lahar and beyond. Were
these drones primarily deployed to map
Pakistan's urban and defense
infrastructure in real time? Or did
these drones have some other purpose
other than striking the air defense and
mapping their infrastructure? Look, the
primary uh objective of these drones was
to uh strike the targets. Whichever
targets were chosen uh to be hit, the
targets were military targets, uh air
defense systems, uh radar systems and
other military uh infrastructure of
Pakistan. And that was imp placed within
cities like Lahore. So the air defense
system for for Lahore was near the
Lahore airport and that was taken out
and wiped out obliterated uh by today's
strikes uh in the daytime daylight
strikes. Um so today's drone strikes
they penetrated the Pakistani air
defense system. They they were able to
just go through the Pakistani air
defense defense system and the
Pakistanis are claiming that 25 drones
or whatever were shot down. But look, we
know the damage our drones caused in
Pakistan. It's it's all over social
media and uh it's unmistakable that
significant damage was caused and and
and significant targets were hit in
Pakistan and their their own citizens
are reporting. See today in this age of
social media, you can't hide these
things. Pakistan has been claiming that
they shot down five Indian aircraft,
right? Fighter planes. Well, in today's
day and age, if such a thing happens,
you can't hide it. It will be all over
social media. Let's say Pakistan takes
out an Indian aircraft and the Indian
aircraft falls in Indian territory on on
the Indian side of the border. Well,
locals are going to film it and it's
going to end up on social media whether
you like it or not. That's how today's
day and age is. Everybody has a cell
phone with a camera. Everybody can
instantaneously upload it to social
media and it'll be all over the social
media. You simply can't contain this
information. You can't hide it. You
can't keep it secret. So in today's day
and age, you can't lie about these
things. So Indian drones hit multiple
targets, multiple significant high value
targets in Pakistan today and they
bypass the Chinese air defenses, the
Chinese-made air defense systems, right?
They penetrated the air defenses and uh
so look, the primary objective was to
take out the military targets which were
successful. The secondary objective, I'm
sure, was to test the reliability and
and robustness of the Pakistani air
defense system. The Chinese radars and
the Chinese missiles and all that. And
well, it's clear that we were able to
penetrate the Pakistani air defenses.
The Chinese systems aren't that great.
Clearly, and these are some of China's
best air defense systems, the radars and
whatnot. So that is a huge blow to the
prestige of Chinese technology and the
Chinese are going to be worried about
this now. They have been exposed. They
have been exposed. So look these strikes
which we did today. They served multiple
purposes. First of all to give a give a
response to what Pakistan tried last
night to target more than 15 Indian
cities. The Pakistanis last night while
when most while most Indians were
sleeping they attempted to target more
than 15 Indian cities with missile and
drone
attacks and there's videos of the Indian
air defense system taking out these
missiles. You can see the flashes of
light the explosions in the sky or
Punjab and other places even all the way
down south in BJ in Gujarat. We haven't
opened the map today. So let me open the
map in in case some of you are not aware
of where BJ is, let me show
you. Excuse me. So here we have the
map. So the northernmost attempt by
Pakistan to target an Indian city was in
Sinagar apparently. Uh so they tried to
target Shinagar last night. Where's
Shinagar? Oh here it is. And Aantipura
as well. And they t tried to target
multiple uh cities in in
Punjab, Hurana apparently Rajasthan and
the southernmost city they tried to hit
was BJ in western India in Gujarat in
western Gujarat in the Kacho region of
Gujarat. So the Pakistanis tried to hit
more than 15 Indian cities last night.
Okay. and not a single Indian city was
hit because if a single missile hit it
would have been on social media. You
can't hide that in today's day and age.
So Pakistan's attempts to respond to
retaliate to India were were a miserable
failure and then in respon response to
that we launched the strikes today in
the daytime. So the first objective was
to respond to Pakistan's provocation.
The second objective was to to hit the
targets uh that we we had chosen. The
third uh objective was to see how well
we can bypass the Chinese uh made air
defenses of Pakistan and to test the
robustness of the air defense system and
maybe it's possible that these drones
also collected some intelligence you
know signals intelligence visual
intelligence and so on. So it it solved
multiple it served multiple purposes.
The Baron Zemo says, "In your
assessment, what's the likelihood of
Pakistan escalating the situation either
through proxy warfare or through direct
me military means and how should India
handle this in a calibrated manner while
avoiding international pressure? We
don't care about international pressure
anymore. We are past that now." Um, now
the question is excellent. What's the
likelihood of Pakistan escalating the
situation? Look, they're going to
escalate. They're going to try keep on
trying to retaliate and and hit India in
some
manner. What are the ways they could and
first of all why would they do that?
It's because if Pakistan doesn't hit
back at India, then the military will be
seen as important by the people of
Pakistan and then there's going to be
widespread rebellion against the
military because then what is the point
of having the military dictatorship if
they can't even protect Pakistan from
India or or or protect the country's
honor from India and so on. So the
military is has no option but to try and
retaliate against India. It's a it's a
do or die situation. It's a matter of
life and or death for the Pakistani
military. So it is guaranteed they're
going to try then we're going to keep
keep trying something. They are trying
to attack Jammu right now. Just before I
came in to where I am right now, I saw
on TV on sen TV the Pakistani drones
were trying to target Jammu drones or
missiles whatever it was. And I could
see the S S400 in action or whatever
mechanism we were
using. So they are going to keep on
trying this. They're going to try
something. So what are the things they
could try? They'll try and launch
missiles at various Indian cities and we
don't have terror infrastructure. So
they're going to try and hit civilian
infrastructure for Pakistan. Everything
is fine. It's a terrorist nation. So
they're going to try and hit civilians.
Yesterday or day before it was they they
were targeting civilians in in Punchch
in Rajari in Jammu. Uh number of
civilians died. A young brother and
sister you know siblings died and some
six people died. Three sick people in
Gurudala died. And apparently the
Pakistanis tried to launch a missile at
the Golden Temple in Amritsar.
Yeah, they tried to take out the golden
temple in Amritsur and then they would
have I'm sure through their proxies in
the Kalistthani proxies in Canada and
the US they would have tried to pin the
pin the blame on India. That's what they
tried. So they're going to try all these
nefarious methods and the military means
are not going to work because their
military is no match for India's
military and if they hit an Indian city
by some by some means then it's going to
be a significant escalation and India is
going to respond very brutally to that.
Now another thing they can do because
they are a terrorist nation is that they
could try carry out terrorist attacks on
Indian cities. We all know what happened
in Mumbai in 2008. They could try
something like that again. I am sure
they have sleeper cells in India. It's
not hard for a nation like Pakistan to
have sleeper cells in India. Uh let me
assure you of
that. Okay. So they could try something
like that. And unfortunately there are
many Pakistan sympathizers within India.
It's I'm re reiterating the same thing
in a different way but uh you know what
I mean. So that's something they could
try. So we're going to have to be on
high alert. See, we are now a nation at
war. India is a nation at war. India is
going to have to be on high alert. It's
no longer business as usual. You may be
living in a city far from the border.
You may be living wherever you are. You
have to now be on high alert. All
citizens and the government and
government machinery and so on. So
um so what should India do? India will
have to take extra precautions in
civilian places in civilian areas and
cities, towns, villages, wherever else.
We're going to have to be extra alert in
strategic locations like airports and uh
um airports and malls and train stations
and whatnot, ports, all of that. And if
Pakistan tries to escalate through
military means, we should be ready to
take care of that as well. and they're
going to try every means that they have
at their disposal. So yeah, we should
expect more uh mischief from Pakistan
and we should consider oursel ourselves
to be a nation that is now in a state of
war. Anuman Chri says, "What percentage
chance would you give this scenario
escalating into a fully blown nuclear uh
war? a Pakistani retaliation seems
imminent and therefore an Indian one
because India is not going to back down
now anymore. Do you think Pakistan
eventually could resort to their nuclear
weapons in a realistic scenario? Um I
don't think Pakistan will dare resorting
to the nuclear weapons because that
could be the end of Pakistan. And look u
if if the nation is gone then what will
the military rule and what will what
will their legitimacy be be anymore
right? They won't have any legitimacy
anymore. The the military has this
luxurious lifestyle. At least the top
generals and the top brass of the
military. They have this tremendously
luxurious lifestyle. They have
tremendous amounts of money pilered from
the nation from the people of Pakistan.
All their relatives live in the west,
London or in the US or or in in I don't
know whatever other place, right?
and
uh and and so if they lose the nation
that they have then uh whatever power
they have will be gone whatever golden
goose they have Pakistan and its people
that will be gone so it doesn't make
sense to do that and if they have
relatives in Pakistan those those
relatives will also evaporate literally
uh so I think that if push comes to
shove they will decamp and depart out
Pakistan they will escape from Pakistan
and that could leave Pakistan with an
unstable leadership and unstable
scenario in which you have loose nukes
fly floating around that's a very
dangerous situation so we don't want to
go towards that right so I doubt very
strongly that uh Pakistan will even
think of actually genuinely using
nuclear weapons and obviously it is for
us in India and for our military and our
our leadership to ensure that We do this
in a in a calibrated manner. Now the
word calibrated is thrown around a lot
these days. Our strikes were calibrated.
Our response was calibrated. Do you know
what calibration means in in physics?
Calibration means you you measure
something out properly. You you you have
a scale of measurement, let's say
centimeters or inches or whatever. Then
you if you have an instrument that you
want to use to measure something, you
have to uh tune the instrument. let's
say um in by comparing it with an
existing instrument that's already
tuned. It's like tuning a guitar or
something. So that's the process of
calibration to to to be very clear about
what your measurements are and you know
what you want to do with those
measurements. So that's the calibration.
So we're going to have to calibrate our
approach our our uh military approach
towards Pakistan. If you strike at them,
how much do we strike? How hard do we
strike? Where do we strike? Where do we
not strike? What do we not touch? What
do we destroy? and so on. And that's
something you have to really think
through. And that's not something you do
during wartime. You do that during peace
time. You war game all the
scenarios and you simply execute that
during wartime. So we would already have
calibrated out and thought everything
out what our responses could be and
should be to various provocations and
various situ situations and scenarios
and we are simply implementing executing
that right now.
So I don't think it's going to take a
nuclear dimension. And if the Pakistanis
make the incredible mistake of using
nukes where it's the end of the story
for Pakistan, it's not going to be the
end of the world. It's going to be the
end of Pakistan. We may have to absorb
some damage. Sure. But if they use one
nuke, it's the end of Pakistan. That's
that's a promise guarantee. And
look, civilized people should not even
discuss using nukes. Nukes should never
ever be used. You know it's it's a
horrible weapon.
So Dhanush says, "What do you think the
nature of the Pakistani response would
be given that the attacks by India were
publicly visible to the Pakistani
population with a 100% success rate?
They would be under some pressure to
respond or the army's aura of
invincibility they have in Pakistan
would be threatened. Do you really think
they'd try and hit Indian military
installations? in if so what would India
do in my opinion yeah so the question is
how far can this go we're not discussing
the nuclear matter here we already
discussed that in the last question so
what can the Pakistan response be either
they hit Indian military in
installations which is difficult or they
hit Indian civilian areas which is much
easier because it's impossible for any
military in the world to defend every
inch of its territory so it's very easy
to hit Indian civilian areas of course
if you use missiles and we can take it
them out with for uh air defense systems
and so on. S400 but we don't have S400s
everywhere. So uh they could try and hit
Indian civilian targets which could be
pretty bad if that happens. Right? Then
they can try terror attacks and they can
try activating sleeper cells that they
may or may not have within India and
they could try something like they tried
during the Mumbai attacks. You know
these are scenarios that we should be uh
aware of, right? These things could
happen. It's a terrorist nation we're
talking about. they can try anything. Uh
so that's another thing they could try.
Um so the question
is if they do such things, what can
India do in response in my
opinion? Well, if they're going to do
something, we're going to do it twice as
hard, twice as hard. If they hit let's
say an Indian city, okay, if they if one
of their missiles goes through and hits
an Indian city and unfortunately people
um there are casualties, let's say,
civilian casualties, what will India do?
We obviously won't hit a Pakistani city.
We don't do such things. But we're going
to take out some big military
installations and we're going to you
know give them real pain. Not the people
but the military. So that's going to
have that's something that could happen.
If you know if if push comes to shove
then what's the worst thing that could
happen? The worst thing is that India
you know makes a move on Pakistani
territory. what I have spoken about
before a scenario that I call the pulse
pause war. So Indian um infantry, Indian
tanks make a certain move into Pakistan.
Not a blitzkrieg move which is punching
a hole but a wide frontal move and you
take a decent amount of Pakistani
territory move 10 20 30 maybe 50
kilometers into Pakistani territory. You
grab the territory then you unilaterally
declare a pause. That's it. We're going
to stop here. So it's not
life-threatening for Pakistan. It's not
like the whole nation is is going to be
overrun. It's just that we have
delivered a military and political
defeat to you and don't do this again
because next time will be worse. So
that's what I think could happen. And
now I am not giving some special guan to
Pakistan and dulging military secrets. I
am speculating here and these are
scenarios that every military leader,
every military expert will work through
this and 100 other scenarios. Okay. Uh
so that's something that could happen
and and the
Pakistanis militarily are no match for
India. So we would succeed in this and
that's the scenario in which you talk
about you know everybody wants to talk
about taking back P or whatever that
would happen. we would take back musabad
or or lahor probably not lahar because
that's too many people there and we
don't want to deal with them but we
would take territory for sure uh so that
would be a a clear defeat for Pakistan
military and political and that's what
we would do so that's I think as far as
it will go right now and our objective
is to essentially end the legitimacy of
the Pakistani ISI military terrorist um
entity which is seen by the Pakistani
people as being the legitimate ruler of
Pakistan. So we need to show to the
people of Pakistan that this is an
illegitimate organization and the the
one claim that they have that makes them
legit which which gives them legitimacy
that we can defend against India even
that is hollow that's what we have to
show to the Pak people of Pakistan and
then what should happen is that Sinduh
should declare independence Balojasthan
should declare independence Kashmir
should say that P should say we want to
go back to India and Khibar Pakunwa
should open the border with Afghanistan.
That's what needs to happen and that's
the eventual
objective. Dano again says, "What are
your thoughts on what's happening in the
punch sector more where more than 15
civilians have been killed in Pakistani
shelling and many more have been
injured, schools and houses have also
been impacted? How should India handle
the situation?" See, this is classic
Pakistani uh behavior. They can't target
the Indian military. Um so they're going
to target civilians. They tried
targeting the Indian military and didn't
work. Didn't work. So they'll try
targeting Indian civilians and civilians
are a soft target, easy target. It's
such a huge nation. You can't defend
every inch of the territory. So you're
going to always have some civilians who
can easily become targets of Pakistani
uh military terrorism. Right? So that's
what happened in PCH. They they um they
shelled the town and a large number of
people civilians died. It is like
another pahelgam that they have done
right uh that they destroyed a guru
dwara at least three people there died
three sick people and so on so classic
Pakistani behavior targeting in innocent
helpless civilians how should India
handle this by piling on the pain on the
Pakistani military that's going to
continue we are in a state of war and we
have to show the people of Pakistan the
military is illegitimate they can't even
defend you they can't even defend your
territory
Indian nation and themselves the
military can't even defend itself and
its terrorist pets. That's what we what
we have to show to the people of
Pakistan and that's what's
happening. Prayal says that uh with
Pakistan's economy in deep distress
could operation Sindur act as a tipping
point intensifying the internal collapse
of Pakistan and leading to serious
political instability. Today the Karachi
Stock Exchange closed early after a near
7,000 point crash amidst repeated drone
strikes across cities. Trading was
suspended. How do you read this
development in the broader strategic and
regional security context? Are we
witnessing a slow motion unraveling of a
fragile state under calibrated Indian
pressure? That's precisely what's
happening. Yes, this is going to have
multi multi-dimensional impact on
Pakistan. Multiple impacts in multiple
dimensions, domains and areas. uh first
of all it has a deep impact on the
psyche of the people of the of the
nation. The nation as a collectively has
a morale has a psyche and every nation
needs victory to feel good about itself
and when this sort of thing happens it
it leaves a huge scar in your psyche in
the collective consciousness. So the
Pakistani people's morale I promise you
has crashed has plummeted it's it's it's
a negative figures right now. Um, so
that's one thing that's happened. The
army, I I assure the Pakistani
civilians, if this continues, they will
no longer see the army as as a
legitimate uh dictatorial force and
whatever support exists for the army
will evaporate. All the grievances, all
the misrule of the army will come to the
four and there's going to be a
significant uh push back uh against the
army. That that's another thing that
will happen. Economically Pakistan is
already in deep deep deep trouble, dire
straits that's going to worsen, right?
The water situation is going to be
another pain point because we no longer
u uh you know the indust water treaty no
longer stands right the Shimla agreement
is gone but the the water is going to be
a problem. We can, you know, give them a
shortfall of at least 10% of water, 10%
less or more. We can release water uh
abruptly if required. You know, it it
sounds terrible, but that's what you do
to a terrorist nation. There's there's
no other way to make them behave. You
have to do all these things in tandem.
So the water situation is going to be
bad which means that crops will fail and
uh then they will have to import food
food stuffs food grains all that which
already when you have a tottering
economy that that makes things even
worse there's going to be shortages and
who's to blame the army the military the
terrorists they are to blame not India
is not to blame the military is to blame
the Pakistani military so the people
will blame the Pakistani military and
once again that's going to make things
very difficult for the military so
overall you're going to see
disenchantment, disaeffection rising in
Pakistan and then all the old grievances
will come to the four. Synindu des will
want independence. Balojasthan already
wants independence that will that will
come up. Um the pashons want to reunite
with Afghanistan and they should. So
eventually the nation will break up. It
should have broken up a long time ago
but it's always external forces that
have kept it together. Now the US has
taken its hands away. Pakistan now is
once again a creature of China. So the
Chinese will try and perhaps stabilize
Pakistan. They'll try. Let's see how
long and how far that succeeds. So that
is the situation. We are indeed
witnessing the beginning of the slow
motion unraveling of the Pakistan
nation. I said this a couple of weeks
ago that the Pahelgam attack was at
pingpoint. It was an inflection point
point for Pakistan and the countdown for
Pakistan started that day whatever date
it was 25th of April or whatever it was
that was the biggest mistake Pakistan
did in its history and the end the
countdown for Pakistan started that day
the clock is now ticking it's ticking
backwards ticking it's ticking towards
zero it may take it may reach zero in 3
months or 6 months or 3 years or 10
years whenever it does but the countdown
has started it's begun and uh soon
unfortunately time will be up for
Pakistan and I hope it doesn't uh uh you
know cause too much suffering to the
people but if it does well you know who
you know who's to blame it's not us who
is to blame it's your leadership it's
the Pakistani ISI military terrorism
entity that is to blame for everything
that's going wrong in Pakistan you can't
blame India for it we are simply
defending ourselves and we've had
enough. Surendra Gupta says Pakistan is
doing heavy firing in the punch area.
They fired a chi they fired Chinese
missiles on on the night of May the 7th
after the air strike from India and the
Chinese missiles were shot down by the
Indian air defense system. But do you
think a fullscale war is inevitable? I
think we are now possibly entering a
phase of a new
normal. A new normal phase. The old
normal was Pakistan terrorism, crossber
terrorism, infiltration across the LOC,
infiltration across the international
border of terrorists into India and then
this terrorists will unleash mayhem
periodically sporadically in various
parts of India whether it's Punjab or
Jammu and Kashmir or various other
whatever other part of India that was
the old normal and India would simply
try and eliminate the terrorists within
its territory and we would typically not
do take any action across the border.
That was the old normal. The new normal
I believe could be this state of war,
low inensity war
possibly. Now the
Pakistanis, they may still keep on
trying to infiltrate terrorists, but now
we're going to be bombarding their
positions. We're going to be taking out
Pakistani installation, military
installations and terrorism
installations. We're going to go after
the terrorists in a multiplicity of
ways. So a a low inensity war is already
in effect right now. Uh could it become
a full-scale war? It all depends on the
choices that Pakistan makes going
forward. If they target civilians,
that's going to be you know the one
thing the Indian government will not
tolerate is Pakistan targeting
civilians, Indian civilians. We've lost
too many civilian lives, innocent lives
and the government will not tolerate
that anymore. If they target civilians,
it's India will respond like 10 times as
hard and we won't target their civilians
will target their military and then
let's see whatever happens. We'll see.
So it's it's up to Pakistan what choices
the Pakistanis make. What choices does
Aim Munir make and his generals and his
military make? That is what's going to
determine whether a full-scale war
happens. And if it happens, it's going
to be a pulse pause war. 72 hours at
most. 72 hours at most. After which we
will declare a unilateral pause after
taking Pakistani territory. And then
we're going to tell them you want more
of this, let us know. We can do more. We
can do this forever. So yeah, a war, a
genuine war, a highintensity war is
certainly possible depending on the
choices the Pakistanis make.
Ro Rudand belt initiative says I have
noticed the the hate for Hindus in
Pakistan is much more than other
religions. Um it's unfortunate but true.
You know in India there are lots of
people who say that you know we are the
same people. Uh we are the same blood.
We have the same ancestors, same
culture, same uh traditions. Apart from
religion everything is the same. True.
Sure. Okay. Wonderful. We are the same
blood. Look I am from western India.
Okay. uh Pakistan is is a next door
state for me for for the for for you
know the region that I my heritage is
from. So I I know I will have relatives
across the border. I not close relatives
but distant relatives for sure
guaranteed. We are all related to each
other in India. You go back 20
generations half of the country is
related to each other. We may not
realize it. We may not know it but we
are. So we all have blood relatives in
Pakistan and they hate us. You know
blood doesn't matter unfortunately. DNA
doesn't matter. If it mattered then
Greece and Turkey would not be enemies.
Who are the people of Turkey? They are
converted Greeks but they want every
Greek person dead. Do you understand
that? Blood doesn't matter. Sadly DNA
doesn't matter. It's your culture that
matters. And Pakistan's culture sadly is
that of hatred. I'm not saying all
Pakistanis hate Hindus and all
Pakistanis hate India. Some of them
don't. And I'm glad some of them don't.
We have some viewers on this channel who
are from
Pakistan. Um but
sadly the majority of Pakistan hates
India. Most Pakistanis hate Hindus.
They'll be happy to see us bleed
literally. I would say maybe 90% of
Pakistanis hate Hindus and hate India
and it's it's drilled into them. It's
indoctrinated into them from their
childhood onwards. Maybe it's not their
fault. Let's say but what can I do about
it? Right?
Somebody let's say somebody has been
brainwashed into thinking that he should
kill me. I know it's not his fault that
he was brainwashed but hey, I've got to
defend myself. So either he dies or I
die. That's sadly where we are. Sadly,
so yes, you know, there are these people
in India who say that, you know, we are
the same people and we should not hate
the Pakist I don't hate Pakistani
people. I have met lots of Pakistanis
outside of the country. You go anywhere
in the west, you'll meet
Pakistanis. You go to the US, you go to
the UK, you go to Europe, you'll meet
Pakistanis. You go to even the Gulf
region, you'll meet
Pakistanis. Um that's how it is. And
most Pakistanis as individuals are are
nice people.
you know uh but deep down most of them
maybe 90% of them hate Hindus and hate
India sadly and it's so sad that we are
in the situation but it is what it is so
we have to remember that okay please
remember that and uh if you have any
sense you should uh not hate them back
but be aware that they'll do they'll be
happy to do anything to you. So we've
got to take care of ourselves. We've got
to look out for ourselves in our
self-defense. That's what we have to
understand. We have to understand the
nature of the enemy. We may not see them
as enemies, but they see his as enemies.
So we are enemies then.
Right there. There we have it. That's
how it
is. Okay. This is a big question. Samart
says why did Chinese origin air defense
systems
HQ9/PLY80 HQ22 HQ11 and FN6 man pads
deployed by Pakistan during India's
operation Synindur fail to
intercept various kinds of Indian cruise
missiles and drones and scalp cruise
missiles and other aerial threats? What
do what does the downing of a Pakistani
JF17
Nakur and the discovery of two PL-15E
missile debris you know Sharpur Punjab
reveal about the shortcomings of
Pakistani of of Chinese missile missile
systems. Could these failures be
attributed to China's reliance on
reverse engineered technologies and its
lack of major war experience since the
1979 sign of Vietnam war? With China not
having engaged in a major war for
approximately 46 years. If China were to
engage in future conflicts such as over
Taiwan or in the South China Sea, could
similar failures in missile and jet
interception occur due to untested
technologies and other factors? That's a
great question. Long question, but great
question. You are right. Your
observation is correct. China hasn't
been involved in a major war since the
1979 defeat to Vietnam. They were
defeated by Vietnam in 1979. I'll not go
into the history of why that happened,
but they were defeated by Vietnam. A
much smaller and much weaker apparently
nation, right? Um since then, the
Chinese have not fought in a war and um
they have a huge military budget.
They're the second largest military
budget in the world and they apparently
have very good technology and all that
but that is untested and yesterday and
day before yesterday it was tested and
it
failed. Pakistan is equipped with
Chinese uh air defense systems and those
failed
miserably. So that's a blow to the image
and prestige of Chinese technology and
it raises serious question marks about
whether the Chinese can defend
themselves in similar situations.
Right. Uh I am not sure about the
downing of the Pakistani jet. It looks
like at least one JF7 has come down but
the Indian government has not made any
official statements about this. So I'm
not going to comment about this right.
It's not officially stated but it is
almost certain that at least one
Pakistani JF7 came down in um Indian
territory. Um but since the government
is not has not said anything I'll I'll
not you know speculate about that. Now
two Chinese missile debris were found in
Osharpur. So those were longrange
missiles fired apparently at Indian
fighter planes which indicates that
probably India used fighter planes in
the operation on the Indian side of the
border or LOC right we did not cross the
LOC or the international border but we
flew within our our territory. It looks
like that. And the Pakistanis apparently
tried to take out our fighter planes
using these long range Chinese missiles.
Those also
failed, right? Uh and the missile debris
have been discovered and they will now
be examined by experts, by engineers and
scientists, which which will be good. Um
so it looks like there are big problems
with Chinese defensive systems and
offensive systems. The missiles did not
hit their intended targets and uh the
Chinese
radars did not work. They did not detect
the incoming drones which if they did
would have been shot down. I would
expect lots of drones hit the targets.
Uh the Chinese missile the Chinese
radars and air defense systems did not
detect India's loitering drones which
were calmly filming the strikes that we
were doing on the on the Pakistani
terrorist infrastructure. Those videos
were filmed by Indian loitering drones.
They were not filmed filmed by a
vlogger, right? We had drones on over
those those terrorist
uh headquarters and all that. Calmly
loitering and filming and the Pakistanis
could not hit those
drones.
Incredible. So big questions now arise
about the quality of these Chinese
systems. Apparently the Chinese had sold
their best systems, the highquality
systems, not the export versions but the
real versions to the Pakistanis and
those have failed miserably. Um so I I
don't want to speculate as to why these
failures happened and can we attribute
this to the fact that the Chinese have
reverse engineered various western
technologies? I don't know. Maybe it's
because they've reverse engineered in a
poor way. Maybe maybe they developed it
on their own. I don't know about that.
Okay. um our experts will examine those
missiles and their radars and seekers
and all that and we'll get some
interesting information from
that. But obviously those missiles don't
work. Our missiles are better. But
anyway, there's no harm re you know um
uh there's no harm taking apart the
enemy's systems and examining them so
that we understand we get an
understanding of their capabilities,
technological capabilities.
So yeah, it's it's good to know that the
Chinese systems don't work very well.
They didn't work at all unfortunately
for the Pakistanis and for the
Chinese. Next by
Pranipal. With the heat of operation
Sindur and pressure mounting on
Pakistan, how do you assess China's
silent but calculative posture
especially with with its interest in
Pakistan occupied Jammu and Kashmir
through the China Pakistan economic
corridor? Could this evolving situation
corer China into choosing be between its
economic ambitions and regional
stability? Is Pakistan occupied Jammu
and Kashmir emerging as a real
geopolitical fault line in Asia right
now? Um yeah, but see the Pakistanis no
longer have the master have they've been
served divorce papers by America. In
2022, the Americans conducted a regime
change operation in Pakistan. They had
Imran Khan ousted and uh the Sharif
fellow Shbaz Sharif became the prime
minister the the the nominal prime
minister of Pakistan. What really
happened is that the Americans once
again took charge of the Pakistan
military. The military switched its
allegiance to the Americans and they put
a puppet prime minister in place and
Pakistan became once again a US vasal.
In 24 the same thing happened in
Bangladesh. Shikharina was ousted and
Bangladesh was turned into East
Pakistan. Both these things happened
under the Biden regime, right? With
Trump coming to power, the Americans
have washed their hands off Bangladesh
as well as Pakistan. So Pakistan is now
fishing for a new master and obviously
that master can only be China. There's
nobody else that can play that role. And
the same thing is happening in
Bangladesh. Muhammad Yunus was in China
and he was he was saying that you know
we can cut India's far east northeast
off and make it a landlocked place and
that's why Pakistan that's why China
should invest in Bangladesh and so on.
So both east and west Pakistan are
fishing for a new master in Beijing. Uh
and Beijing will be happy to oblige.
Right? So China has taken the side of
Pakistan. You know everybody after the
the the terror attack happened in
Pahelgam most civilized nations uh
issued statements in support of India
and in solidarity with India. Most
civilized nations did. I don't think
I've seen China issue any
statement. So, China has chosen not to
stand on the side of civilized nations.
Right? So, that's one thing we have
seen. Now, after India struck back at
Pakistan and paid them back in in in a
language they understand. The Chinese
criticized India and and they stood in
favor of Pakistan. They made statements
in favor of Pakistan. Now we know that
the Pakistan that the Chinese have this
project this failed project this
miserably failed project called the
China Pakistan economic corridor which
is an extension of their failed built in
road initiative right but it's a project
that the Chinese have invested
significant amounts of money in billions
of dollars and it gives them strategic
access to to Pakistan to the Pakistan
occupied Kashmir region to the port um
in in Guada AR and that's valuable for
the Chinese. So they would like to uh
retain their their their control and
hold over this right and now that
Pakistan is once again a Chinese vas
they would want
to exert more control over the all these
pieces of infrastructure.
So now that operation synindur is
ongoing and India and Pakistan are at
war and Pakistan is on the receiving end
and Pakistan could you know if things
continue like this it it could
spontaneously combust and disintegrate
that would be bad for China that would
be terribly bad for China. Uh so China
has been making statements in favor of
Pakistan.
Um could they actually try and come to
ch to to Pakistan's rescue or aid? Uh
their economic ambitions are faltering.
The tariffs that the Americans have
imposed that Trump has imposed on China
are really hurting. I assure you that
they are hurting. Right. So
um so China is currently in a state
under a state of siege. it is
besieged and u if and and it essentially
has only two vasals in the world. One is
North Korea, one is Pakistan. Russia
isn't a Chinese vasal. Russia is uh
sadly currently in a position of being
kind of a junior partner to China
because of China's enormous economic
clout. Uh but Russia is not exactly a
pushover. It's kind of a junior partner
right now for now. But China and Russia
are long-term strategic adversaries, not
allies. So, China has a few friends. One
is Russia for now. It's it's a
strange modus vendi they have with with
Russia. They have two vasals in in in
North Korea and Pakistan. And they also
have a strategic ally in Iran because of
the West's attitude and approach towards
Iran. So, Iran had no choice but to look
towards Russia and China for help.
Right?
Um so now if Pakistan shows signs of uh
soon disintegrating what can Pak what
can China do about this? Can they
somehow stabilize Pakistan? They can
certainly stabilize Pakistan by by
giving a huge inflow of money to
Pakistan. They can do that but money
can't really help you much when your
nation is is fragmenting right and is is
China in a position to shore up
Pakistan's defenses it can certainly
supply weapons that takes time but they
can try and do that but if China tries
to get directly involved in Pakistan
they're going to you know it's not going
to end well for them also so China is
right now going to be in a dilemma right
now it's not the situation isn't that
are bad. Pakistan isn't showing signs as
of right now of of soon disintegrating.
But the longer this war situation lasts,
right now it's just 2 days. But what if
it becomes two weeks and this becomes
the new normal? The Pakistanis try to
keep on striking India and India keeps
on actually striking Pakistan and it it
it India keeps on jabbing away. In
boxing there is this this punch called
the jab. You just keep on jabbing
jabbing jabbing jabbing and over 10
rounds you can rearrange a person's
furniture facial furniture just by one p
the jab. So if India keeps jabbing at
Pakistan, jabbing, jabbing, jabbing, in
two weeks time Pakistan's furniture will
be significantly rearranged and the
nation's morale will be at an abysmal
low and the people could stand up and
and you know you go up in arms against
the military and then the the military
will see their own people as the enemy
and that will be a huge issue. Then
India can just step back and watch you
know and then what can China do? So it's
it's China could soon be in a big
dilemma if the situation continues. If
the current state of war becomes the new
normal, if it persists beyond 3 or 4
days, if it lasts two weeks or two
months, good god, it's the end of
Pakistan and China really won't know
what to do. So
yeah, Pranal has asked a lot of good
questions. So I'm taking those. uh if
the situation around Pakistan occupied
Jammos and Kashmir escalates and leads
to Pakistan's fragmentation or
balkcanization what should we
realistically expect from China
especially regarding China Pakistan
economic corridor Gilg with Baltistan
its growing presence in Baluchasthan
will China double down to secure its
strategic interests or might it quietly
reposition and retreat to avoid global
backlash how should India prepare for
any ch potential Chinese moves amidst
Pakistan's internal collapse
We should be ready for all
eventualities. Look the Chinese
have a small border with
Pakistan. Uh the you know Pakistan
occupied Jammu and Kashmir and Tibet
have a border right and the Pakistanis
in the past they gave away the Shakcom
Valley to the Chinese and so on. So
there's a small corridor. I mean let's
take a look at the map. We have hardly
opened the map today. Uh let's take a
look at the map and see what kind of a
geographical situation the two nations
share. So let's zoom in to the northern
part of India and uh as you can see you
know so this shows the correct map of
India. Google has been kind enough to do
that. But um the truth is that Gul
Gilgit and Hunza Nagar etc. These
portions of Jammu and Kashmir are
currently temporarily under Pakistani
occupation and it abetss on
u this part of Chinese occupied
territory the the the Shinjang region
right the Sinjang region not the Tibet
region but the Shinjang region so um
there is a
small uh border let's say boundary
between Chinese occupied territory and
Pakistan occupied territory but it's
tremendously mountainous let's let's
take Take a look at the actual
topography of the region. As you can
see, it is extremely mountainous and you
can't really drive tanks through it or
some or or it's it's really hard to
navigate this terrain on foot on tank or
on armored vehicles or even jeeps.
That's how difficult it is. So if if
China if if Pakistan is showing signs of
let's say
disintegrating. Okay. Um it's it's going
to be really hard for the Chinese to
step in and and stop that. It's going to
be really hard for the Chinese to stop
that. They I'm sure they'll be tempted
to do that do that but it won't be easy.
But India should be aware of the
possibility of the Chinese trying
something. They have a road that goes
into into Pakistan occupied Kashmir. And
the Chinese have had in the past few
years a history of doing military uh
military drills with Pakistan in
Pakistan occupied Kashmir. And maybe
there is some Chinese small or medium
scale Chinese military presence in
Pakistan occupied Kashmir. Maybe in uh
Balojasthan as well. So the Chinese
presence is there to some extent in in
Pakistan in various parts of Pakistan
especially those parts of Pakistan that
are of our interest because of well all
of Pakistan is of our interest for
historical reasons but you get you get
what I mean. So the Chinese may try to u
try they may try to stabilize Pakistan
if it is showing signs of
disintegrating. So India should be very
much aware of this and if push comes to
shove and we have to take military
action, we should factor in the
possibility of a Chinese uh presence or
element that we have to deal with
militarily in the region. So I'm sure
it's already been factored in into all
our uh calculations already. I'm sure.
I'm pretty
sure. Mr. Atus says out of topic. Not
really out of topic. It's actually on
topic but good question. Why is it that
India has received countless u uh
numbers? Yeah. Why has India been so
much at the receiving end of western
sponsored terrorism at the hands of
Pakistan? Good question. But China
hasn't ever been at the receiving end of
Western sponsored terrorism. Even though
China has proved to be the West's
biggest enemy and the West literally
sits at the back of the Chinese yard.
Okay. So what Mr. 88 is saying is that
we know that India that Pakistan has
bled India through terrorism essentially
since 1979 and it has done so at the
behest of the US of the west of the UK.
The Pakistani defense minister has said
this at least two times in the past two
weeks and even Bilawal Bhau the son of
Benaz Bhau has said this on western
media on Sky TV I think at least once.
So now the Pakistanis have admitted that
they have been doing this. They have
been indulging in terrorism against
their their neighbors especially India
at the behest of the west. They have
been doing it for the west to serve the
western geopolitical interests. They
were simply mercenaries. They were
simply service providers. They have
admitted this. So it becomes very clear
now that what I have been saying for the
past two three years is now vindicated.
It's true.
India has
suffered from terrorism at the hands of
Pakistan. Terrorism that was funded and
financed primarily by the United States
from the 1970s and 80s onwards. Very
clear that it is proven now. Pakistan
has admitted this on the record.
Pakistan government officials extremely
highranking government officials have
admitted this. So India has been at the
receiving end of western
terrorism right for decades but done by
Pakistan. But how come China hasn't been
treated that way by the
west? It's because the Chinese were
smart and we were
not. You see our leaders weren't smart.
The Chinese were smart. The Chinese they
they tricked the
west into aiding and abetting the rise
of China, the economic and industrial
rise of China. The West midwifed this.
The West
opened their market to the Chinese. So
the West wanted cheap manufacturing and
they gave it to China. They gave their
technology to China. They had China
manufacture everything. They gradually
transferred more and more sophisticated
technology to to China and the Chinese
became masters in a few decades of all
these manufacturing processes and all of
these technologies and they absorbed all
the technology. So they became a huge
manufacturing power because the west
allowed this and the west you know the
Chinese told the west you know you teach
us all these things and slowly we will
become like you. the west and the
Americans thought that by opening our
markets to to the Chinese we'll
eventually make them a democratic nation
by seeing how superior we are and all
that eventually they'll become a
democracy like us that's what they
thought and the exact opposite of of
that happened the Chinese played a very
very smart
intelligent long game and we in India
played a stupid game our leaders played
a stupid game we could have done that.
We were already a nation that had a lot
of exposure to the west because of the
250 years of British occupation of
India. We were familiar with western
ways. We could have been the
manufacturing power. We could have done
all of that but we chose not to. We
chose to be a socialist nation and we
chose to sit on the side of the USSR
which is
okay. But we we kept on harping our our
leaders kept on harping on that we are a
non-aligned nation while actually
aligning with the
USSR. And what did we gain by aligning
with the USSR? Did we gain technology?
Did we ask for it? Did we say to the
USSR that you stop manufacturing, we'll
manufacture, we'll manufacture
everything for you. We did none of that.
We had no vision. Our leaders had no
vision.
So we were simply an inconvenient nation
that lied that liked to uh take the
moral high ground and lecture the
world and not take care of our interest.
So that's why the west that's why the US
decided to invest in Pakistan instead of
India and use Pakistan as a
counterbalance to
India. Had we played the game better,
had we been smart about it, we could
have been the Chinese. We could have
been China. But our leaders had no
vision. They had no
standards and that's why we were at the
receiving end of decades of western
funded and financed Pakistani terrorism
and China were not because our leaders
were stupid that's why that's this is a
great question Mr. Ediator has
asked really now says looks like the
facade of any India China friendship is
now over but we let shine and other
brands in in partnership with Reliance
I'm not sure about that but okay uh did
the government do good by not applying
not not approving the BYD investment but
then what about the Chinese needing the
Indian market they must have a good plan
and options since they've decided to
finally openly resume to show hostility
at least in the UN and on social media.
Uh anyway, it's clear that we are on the
western camp for the first time since
independence. Ho ho what's the way
forward. We are when it comes to China,
we are now on the western camp clearly
and the west will have been told by us
that you keep out of the India Pakistan
matter. Let us deal with Pakistan. You
tell the Pakistanis to to tone it down
otherwise we're going to be very harsh
on them. And don't pressure us. If you
want us to be on your side visa v China,
you got to stay out of the Pakistan
matter and let us deal with it. That
will be the deal. And that's why Trump
is staying out of it. Very clearly
staying out of it. Very openly staying
out of
it. Now the past year or so, the Chinese
have been trying to be friends with us.
Uh I am personally aware of the Chinese
attempts to be friends with us.
Um so uh and then there's been some some
actual action on the ground. Um in 2020
there was the DLAM incident. 20 Indian
troops died at the hands of the Chinese
and about 100 Chinese troops died at the
same fight.
Um, ever since then the two armies, the
two nations have been engaged in this
very tense standoff in the Himalayan
Heights uh along the undemarcated India
Tibet border, Chinese occupied
Tibet and um soldiers standing in
incredibly high altitudes, 8,000
uh meters at times. Uh if you go to
Ladak, it's hard to to walk for most
people, you know.
um there's very little oxygen up there
in the in in those heights and you have
soldiers who have to carry equipment and
all. So it's it's very grueling, very
very um very difficult and hundreds of
thousands of soldiers on both sides
staring each other down from close
range. That's the situ that's what the
situation was like. The past one year
there's been one could say significant
disengagement from both sides. So the
the tensions have come down, the
temperature has come down, patrolling uh
has resumed in the old style in the old
areas and all that and u yeah the
hostilities have come down the
possibility of something going really
badly wrong between the two nations has
also come down but at the same time the
Chinese are doubling down on
infrastructure on their side of the
border. So it's not like so the close
proximity standoff is gone but the
Chinese are you know entrenching
themselves and and uh enhancing their
military infrastructure on the Tibet
side of the border. So it's not like all
is well the Kailash manser over Yatra
will resume soon. So there are some
so-called confidence building measures
and all and uh the
Chinese they they probably did this
because they could sense that the
western markets were soon going to be a
thing of the past for them. They would
no longer have access to it and that's
precisely what's happened with the
tariffs that Trump has imposed on them.
So the Chinese probably thought that we
can we would like to have access to the
Indian market and if we you know show
signs of friendship then that could
happen. So if we lose the access to the
western and European markets and
American market then we can have access
to the Indian market and we can keep uh
exporting to the Indians. That probably
was uh a scenario that they were trying
to uh make
happen. But now with whatever has
happened now they have chosen to stand
on the side on the side of Pakistan. So
um that that's the end of that that's
the end of the uh so-called India China
haposhimo that supposedly was happening
uh I don't see that happening anymore um
I'm not sure about shine or whatever it
is uh who has come in we can always ask
them to leave if that's the case and I'm
not sure about the BYD investment either
I'm not really looked into those matters
so I cannot answer your question but big
picture macro perspective u the the
India China is is now a thing of the
past
clearly. Mrianka Seeker Biswis says with
the Chinese state media amplifying false
narratives about India's operation
synindur. Yeah, good point. Good point.
Uh Beijing's defense technology
stumbling in a visibly tighter China
Pakistan access. Are the Chinese
officially now playing big daddy hood to
Pakistan in the Indian subcontinent's
power games? The short answer is yes.
The Chinese are the new big daddy of
Pakistan. Pakistan is now a Chinese
vasal once again. For the majority of
the 20th century, they were a US vasal.
Um, in the early 2000s, they were a US
vasal. Once Osama bin Laden was
discovered and taken out allegedly by
the Americans, the Americans then kind
of lost interest in Pakistan. And for a
decade or so from maybe 10 2012 to 2022
the Pakistanis were a Chinese vasal
state. In 2022 for a brief period of
time the Americans took over again. They
affected a regime change operation in
Pakistan. They ousted Imran Khan threw
him into jail and brought a new puppet
prime minister into power. Shabbash
Sharif who is not in power is just in in
his
seat. And for a while the Chinese the
Pakistanis again became an American
masal that was during the Biden regime.
Now Biden is gone. Trump is in power and
Trump wants India on his side. So out
with Pakistan. He is no longer
interested in Pakistan. So Pakistan is
now fending for itself. They the
Pakistanis have been served divorce
papers by the Trump administration. So
they are now looking for a new big daddy
and obviously that's China and China
will be happy with that. So China is yes
now the big daddy of Pakistan in the
region right and you know for a while
for a few months the Chinese media was
saying nice things about India the
global times was talking about India and
China in a nice manner. The Global Times
is a very harshly virulent uh media
outlet. It's an official state uh
Chinese state media outlet.
But the past two days they have been
trying to amplify China uh Pakistan's
false claims about shooting shooting
down I don't know how five Indian
aircraft and so on absolute lies but the
Chinese state media has been amplifying
that and I tweeted what next are you
going to claim that the the Pakistan is
shot down a fleet of Indian UFOs and
what what else so uh yes so the the
Chinese media was very much it's it's
still in the process of amplifying u
lies is Pakistani lives about India's
operations in the world. So yes, the
Chinese are very much on Pakistan's side
and they are now officially Pakistan's
big daddy. The Americans
have, you know, moved away from Pakistan
because they need India on their side in
the entire big geopolitical reset that
we are seeing right now. A huge a huge
geopolitical reshuffle happening in real
time in the world. You can see it
happening day by day. The world order is
rearranging itself. It is being
rearranged by these power moves of the
US and other nations and India has to
decide where it stands in the matter and
it's a complicated game. When it comes
to when it comes to Pakistan, we are
very much on the side of the
west. But when it comes to Russia, it's
complicated. We are not that much on the
side of the west. We will not give up on
our relationship with Russia. We may
make people believe for a while that it
is so. For
example, for example, I mean I even I I
am guilty of amplifying that for a
little bit. Let me tell you what
happened. So
um on the 9th of May, there is the
Russia victory day parade in Moscow and
Mr. Putin has invited uh President
Xinping. President Shrimping has already
reached Moscow. Mr. Putin had also also
invited Prime Minister Modi to attend
the same event. uh Prime Minister Modi
uh said he he uh could not attend the
event. He um and he had nominated Mr.
Mr. Rajnat Singh to attend the event.
India's defense minister. So a very high
ranking minister was supposed to go to
Moscow and attend the event. But then
two days ago even Mr. the Rajnat Singh
pulled out right and uh so it was a good
time to tell the west that you know what
India is becoming closer to the west and
you can expect more India west tango in
the next few months and India is now
distancing itself from
Russia but the actual reason why Mr.
Modi and Mr. Rajnut Singh pulled out
from the May 9 event is because there
was another event planned for May 7th
which was operation synindur right and
so on.
So yeah that's that's what actually
happened. Okay photo one Patel says is
war with China inevitable regardless of
who's in power in China? Why do the
Chinese feel threatened uh when it comes
to India? Look, war with China is not
even inevitable, but if we are not
careful, we could get embroiled in a war
with China. Under what circumstances
could we get embroiled in a war with
China? If the Chinese don't respect us
enough and are not scared of us enough,
then we could get embroiled in a war
with China. See, the one thing that we
have that is on the same level as China
is the nuclear option. uh officially if
you look at official western figures
they said the Chinese have about 600
warheads and we have about 172 or
something warheads so there's a
discrepancy but when it comes to nuclear
weapons even one is enough right but it
is also true that no sane power no
rational power actually wants to use
nuclear weapons so if you take the nukes
out of the picture that there's a huge
disparity in the hard power of China
versus the hard power of India the
Chinese are about three and a half times
more powerful than India
India is small compared to China. China
is three and a half times bigger. If
India is 10 ft tall, China is 35 ft
tall. Do you get it? That's what I mean.
That's by simply measuring hard power,
raw hard power, economic and military
power put together essentially plus
other other factors.
So as long as the Chinese feel that a
war with India will be will end will end
badly for them as long as they feel that
way there won't be a war with India. But
if they feel that India can be pushed
over and it'll be advantageous for the
Chinese to go to war with India before
India gets too big then probably war is
inevitable. So the way to ensure there
is no war is to be forever prepared for
war. The only way you can have peace is
by always be being ready for war. It's a
paradoxical
thing. So it means that India has to
invest in its military. India has to
keep investing more in its military
budget. Maybe India needs to raise its
military budget. Now that we are in a
situation of war with Pakistan, Chinese
may want to get involved. India should,
I think, ramp up its military budget.
See in
2021 number one military budget was
America. Number two was
China. Number three was who was
it? Perhaps it was India. But today's
India is number four. Why? Because
Russia has shot up ahead of us. Russia's
economy is way smaller than the Indian
economy. But Russia's military budget is
way ahead of us now because they are in
a situation of war. the Ukraine war
which is a proxy war against NATO. So
very when you are in that situation you
have to invest more in your military and
you can do it without destroying your
economy because by investing in the
military you can actually set up more
industry more industries more
manufacturing industries which will
generate employment and much more for
the country. So you can create a
military economy that's good for the
country and also ramps up the military
strength of the country. So I think it
may be time for India to start in to
start raising its military budget.
Right? Uh it's something we should think
about. The main thing is the Chinese
will not go to war with India as long as
they respect and fear us. Respect and
fear are essentially two sides of the
same coin. You don't respect someone you
don't
fear. Okay? Mostly in the world of
geopolitics and hard power, respect and
fear are are synonymous.
So they have to be afraid of us to a
certain extent and they have to be
afraid that if they go to war with India
they'll end up losing more than they
will gain. Only in that case in that
scenario will they choose not to go to
war with India. But if you have this big
nation of India and if breaking it up
into multiple pieces will be
advantageous for the Chinese they may
seriously consider war with India. So
war is not inevitable. War will not
happen as long as we take the right
precautions. We have to rise as as a
military power as well as as an economic
power and we have to be smart in doing
that. We have to
especially see we are a missile
superpower. We have some of the best
missiles in the world but we also need
to uh invest in the naval aspect of our
military. We need to become a genuine
maritime power. We need to be visible
all across the Indian Ocean. It's called
the Indian Ocean. But when you are there
in the Indian Ocean, do you see an
Indian presence there? The Indian
presence should be constant. Wherever
you go, you should you should come
across Indian
warships, right? Then you can say it's
your strategic backyard. And to do that,
you have to stop investing in these
giant obsolete monsters called aircraft
carriers. You have to invest in scary
stuff like submarines which are
invisible and deadly. you to invest in
cheap but dangerous things like missile
boats. A missile boat which is like it
costs $20 million but it can destroy a
warship with three brahos missiles or
something. So you have to be smart in
doing this. So India needs to take these
measures. Invest in the naval might in
its naval might invest in submarines
invest in various kinds of missiles not
just 50 missiles or 100 missiles of one
type but thousands of missile. We need
to have a stockpile of thousands, maybe
tens of thousands of missiles. Learn the
lessons of the Ukraine war. Learn the
lessons of the Iran Israel uh conflict.
You need a stockpile of tens of
thousands of missiles. A few hundreds
will do
nothing and so on. So, as long as we do
these things, the Chinese won't go to
war with us and then we can focus on
growing our economy. That's what needs
to happen.
Chira Gavasti says considering that the
IndiaPakistan conflict is unfolding
against a complex geopolitical backdrop
including the ongoing Ukraine Russia
tensions, USChina rivalry and the
growing bricks and global south
realignment. How might this strike
reshape India's relations with the West,
Israel, Russia and the Islamic world? Do
you foresee a shift where India's
assertive military posture accelerates
its rise as a system shaping power or
might it invite new pressures and
containment attempts from global
stakeholders threatened by a confident
India? Look, yeah, it's a very good
question and the way we deal with this
conflict the next few days is going to
determine how the world now decides to
look at us. We have the chance of
completely reformulating or or reshaping
the world the way the world sees us.
Thus far the world sees India as a
passive nation. When the Chinese Global
Times makes a cartoon of India, they
grow they draw India as this fat sleepy
elephant. You know we have tigers as
well in the country. We are the world's
number one tiger nation. We have the
most tigers of any nation in the world.
So why but we are not depicted as a
tiger. We are depicted as an elephant
because we are a slow lethargic
slowmoving nation and we are a passive
nation. We have been a punching bag a
soft state thus far. So the elephant is
that kind of you know it it kind of to
some extent embodies those qualities. We
have to de we have to now show the tiger
aspect of India. So if we deal with
Pakistan appropriately in this in this
current war that we are embroiled in, if
we
decisively defeat them militarily and
politically, then the world will have to
see India in a new light. They will have
no choice but to see to look at India in
a new light and then things will then
then India will will be able to leverage
that in a multiplicity of ways.
So yes, what's happening, this conflict,
this new war is unfolding against a very
complex geopolitical backdrop. U the
west has always wanted to to keep India
down to put India in its place to not to
not allow India to to stray off the
reservation or or they want India to
stay in its lane. But now is the time
for India to demonstrate that we are no
longer that soft, weak, passive nation
and we stand up for ourselves and we
mean business. This is the best possible
opportunity. I think if we handle this
current war properly, it's going to be a
new trajectory for India. This is an
inflection point. Bahelgam is a terrible
atrocity the Pakistanis did on India,
but it may have a silver lining. It it
puts India on a new trajectory. I said
it's an inflection point. It's going to
be something that completely reshapes
the way India approaches with with Pak,
you know, approaches Pak the Pakistan
issue and much more. And it is the
beginning of the end for Pakistan. The
the countdown has begun for Pakistan. So
the next few days, the next couple of
weeks are going to be crucial and if
India does things right, then you know
the world will have no option but to
deal with India in a whole different way
now and India will be a completely
different beast going
forward. So if we don't handle it right
then the west will try to pressurize us
and tell us to to to you know stop the
conflict and contain it and all that.
But so it's up to us as to to decide how
to approach this. So we need to inflict.
So in short in essence we need to either
make this the new normal that Pakistan
will be constantly hit by us as long as
they don't behave or we have to inflict
a quick military defeat on Pakistan
ideally by taking some territory. One of
these two things will happen in the next
few days. Yeah it's a prediction I'm
making. One of these two things will
happen in the next few days. either this
becomes the new normal and Pakistan
becomes like Gaza for
Israel. So the way Gaza is for Israel,
Pakistan will be for India. Every time
they do something like a terrorist
strike, we're going to hit them multiple
times and hit them hard and this will be
an ongoing process perhaps or there's a
short sharp war, a pulse pause war and
we take some territory and then we shut
them down. One of these two things will
happen in the next few weeks, next
couple of weeks. So get get gear up for
that I would
say. Pranay Paul says as operation
sindur unfolds how do you view the muted
or cautious response from major global
power so far in is India's calibrated
approach militarily precise yet
diplomatically firm helping shape a new
global perception of India as a
responsible regional power internally
too from air raid drills to
communication strategy. Does this
reflect a deeper national readiness for
sustained geopolitical assertion? It
does very much so. India is no longer
the India of
2019. 2019 we did Balakot right and at
that time it was something unheard of.
Nobody had dreamt that India would do an
air strike on Pakistan from within
Pakistani
territory. The first time since 1971
that India launched an air strike on
Pakistan 2019, right? And yet one of our
guys were shot down and uh we had to
threaten Pakistan with with annihilation
with a night of Brahos Brahos missiles
for them to give to send Abinand
commander Abinandaman back was
2019 that is no longer the case today's
India is 6 years ahead of 2019 it's a
whole different beast today we don't
even need to send fighter planes across
the border we can hit Pakistan at will
from standoff
distances. India is only going to keep
keep getting stronger and more powerful
in this
manner. So India is no longer the India
of 2019 and the world is watching
cautiously right now. They are wondering
what will India do? How will India
approach this? If we show signs of
weakness now then you know it'll be the
same thing. It'll be the same old same
old thing and we may kind of lose a
little bit of credibility.
And uh that will very very much reassure
the west and the world that they they
can handle this India. But if we do what
I have been saying that we inflict a
genuine proper military defeat on
Pakistan or we make this war situation a
new normal for Pakistan that they are
constantly at war with India and they
can't hit India. One of if one of these
two things happens then um it will
completely reshape the way the world
looks at India. A lot of people will be
very very deeply upset about about this.
No qu question about it in the west. Um
and they will try and paint India as a
nonresponsible global power uh regional
power whatever whatever you want to call
it. But it needs to happen right now.
They're waiting and
watching. Um so yeah that's where we are
and we need to you know deal with this
the right
way. Praneal again uh if Pakistan's in
territorial integrity begins to dissolve
post operation Sindor and the pahalam
response how might global financial uh
institutions like the IMF and FATF react
could we see a shift in how rogue or
failing states are economically handled
in the in the multiple world also will
India's assertive diplomacy now become a
blueprint for other rising powers facing
crossber terrorism and proxy warfare
look we are the only major power uh
facing crossber terrorism and proxy
warfare. Nobody else does. Nobody else
faces this and this is a legacy of the
previous cold war. Um so um okay so
that's that's so I address that part of
the question. Now if Pakistan starts
breaking up if its territorial integrity
begins begins to dissolve post operation
Sindur if Baljasthan declares
independence if Sinduh declares
independence if Kibar Pakta opens the
boundary the border with Afghanistan and
says we are now one with Afghanistan
what happens? How does the IMF react?
How does FATF or whatever react? They
can't do much about this first of all,
right? And they can only deal with
sovereign nations. They cannot deal with
nations that are whose boundaries are
evolving and nations that don't really
have a government. When when a nation is
breaking up and its borders are being
reshaped in real time, it means that
nation has no viable government
otherwise that would not happen, right?
So when a nation is is rudderless like
that uh IMF, the World Bank, whoever
they are of no use and they can't do a
thing about it. They just have to wait
it out until the situation stabilizes
and some kind of new governance entity
emerges in that nation and then they can
deal with that.
Um so yeah that's the
thing prrenal says given operation
sindur and India's calibrated but but
firm posture post pahelgam are we
witnessing a shift in India's military
doctrine from reactive deterrence to
proactive containment could this be the
long overdue strategic pivot to
neutralize asymmetric threats
permanently especially with global
backing quiet quietly aligning it hap it
helps if the global backing aligns uh
with what is in your
Uh I think we are definitely witnessing
a shift in a change in India's military
doctrine and this is a change I'm sure
was planned from a long time ago. I'm
sure after Bala court uh the next phase
of retaliation in case something like
this happens was planned. I'm sure this
this process of planning happened over
the course of a few years. But you know
a nation like India has something called
contingency plans. the next time
Pakistan does X we will do this this
this but if Pakistan does Y then we'll
do that that that so we have a set of
contingency plans for each scenario and
these are all preddecided pre worked out
well in advance and when something
happens we simply execute so it means
the doctrinal shift has already
happened so yes you're right this is a
shift in India's doctrine we are now
seeing it in real
We are no longer going to be a reactive
nation that simply tries to deter by
taking out terrorists from within our
borders. Now we're going to go across
the border and take out the terrorist
infrastructure where at the roots. So
yeah, it's long overdue and it's great.
It it's time India behaves like this.
The Baron Zemo says, "Do you do you
believe India now needs to declare or
adopt a clear offensive counter terror
doctrine and state policy given the
repeat provocations we have faced for
decades?" I think it's happening. We are
seeing it in action now. I it's very
clear that the our approach to Pakistani
uh terror uh operations has changed
completely. It's very clear now. So we
have a new doctrine clearly. We don't
announce these things. You know the
Americans like to put out their
doctrines and publish them in the public
domain. You can go to their websites and
you can see their current doctrine which
may not be the exact doctrine. I'm sure
there is a secret doctrine as well which
is not for public consumption but they
try to the Americans have a policy of
making everything public. We also have
military
doctrine but we don't make it public. So
when the doctrine changes the world can
see it only when it's executed,
implemented. Uh so first of all most
people want to know what a doctrine is
in military terminology. How does things
how do things work? Let's let's go
bottom up. At the very bottom you have
tactical operations, tactical execution.
Tactics are something you train for
tactics. Then above tactics you have
strategy. Strategy. So strategy is one
level above tactics. Then you have grand
strategy. Above grand strategy you have
doctrine. Above doctrine you have policy
which is political policy and that is
married with the worldview the way you
see the world and what your interests
are and so on. So you can create a nice
diagram and show that. But um so
doctrine is it's it's a combination of
of art and science. That's what doctrine
is. It's it doctrine essentially means
this is how we do
things. Okay. And when your doctrine
changes it means that now we no longer
do things this way. We do it now that
way. That's the meaning of a change in
doctrine. So clearly we have changed our
doctrine at least when it comes to uh
dealing with Pakistani terror
activities. PS 1010 says crazy number of
Indians who are not aligned with the
Indian national interest. The blame lies
with the Indian state for creating and
cultivating these groups and keeping the
majority in check for cre for keep for
keeping the majority in check. But now
there are so many groups like that. You
have to look for actual Indians with the
microscope. There are so many Indians
who don't align with the Indian national
interest. What's the reason for this?
Multiple reasons. First of
all, my viewers who are watching right
now and who will see the recorded
version, my question to you is this. Do
you know what the Indian National
Interest
is?
Has anyone taught you what the Indian
national interest is? Did your
school teacher, class teacher, your
textbook teach you what India's specific
national interest is? Did your college
or
university textbooks teach you? No, they
did not. So, you don't know what the
national interest is. Secondly, the
education system does not tell you what
the nation is, what it history is, who
the enemies are. It doesn't tell you
what's right, what's wrong, how to think
properly. So that's why people are they
end up all confused and with wildly
differing worldviews when they come out
of the education system. And their
worldviews are typically shaped by the
last few years of their education in
college and university typically. and
college and university especially when
when you are in the arts and humanities
it's it's shaped by by hard-left
professors and teachers which is why
these these kids the good innocent kids
they end up all polarized and and
indoctrinated with anti-nation ideas and
views and that's that's the fault of the
education system. If you want a
highquality population that's aligned
with the interests of their own
civilization, you need the right kind of
education system. Which is why I've been
saying for so many years, we need to
reform the education system. It's not
enough to strike at
Pakistan. The education system is
creating enemies within India and your
new education policy is like putting a
band-aid. At the risk of repeating
myself, it's like putting a band-aid on
a gunshot wound.
It's high time the government of India
takes education reform
seriously but it doesn't seem like it's
the case. So um yeah there are so many
Indians so many Indians who are not
aligned with the Indian national
interest unfortunately and that's sad
and so visible it's so obvious it's so
out there in your face you
know. Okay, next question of Anvit says,
"Given Pakistan's recent reactions and
the potential for Aim Munir to escalate
tensions in a face saving move, how do
you think India should strategically
position itself to further to prevent
further provocation while ensuring it
remains prepared for any
unforeseen escalation especially in
terms of military readiness, cyber
warfare, international diplomacy?
Diplomatically, we have to talk to
everybody all every all of our friends
and non-friend also. There are lots of
nations who we are on friendly terms
with. We need to engage with them
diplomatically on an ongoing basis and
explain to them what's happening and why
we are doing what we are doing. Okay. We
need to educate them about why are India
and Pakistan fighting each other and who
has started the fight and what's the
cause and so so that's one element the
diplomatic element. We need to talk talk
talk talk to all our friends and even
those who are who may not be very
friendly with us but we need to keep
talking with them engaging with them.
Cyber warfare don't worry about it.
We're good. India is apparently scary
good at cyber warfare. So we don't
discuss it but that's that's as far as I
will tell you uh what I can say. Now
when it comes to military readiness,
what we need to do and ensure is that
there are no shortages of ammunition, no
shortages of anti-missile missiles, air
defense missiles, no shortage, no
shortages of drones, offensive drones,
kamika drones, loitering drones,
offensive missiles. No shortage of spare
parts, no shortage of shells, of of
bullets, of all the essentials.
Everything has to be in available in a
big stockpile in in with with with
enough material for several months of of
conflict if if required. As long as you
have that we're going to be able to
comfortably deal with
Pakistan and of course the strategic oil
reserves and all that. So basic things
you to get right when you're dealing
with a nuisance like Pakistan as long as
there is and of course we have to be uh
on the alert for any terrorist activity
you know Pakistan may be tempted to do
that because that's their nature they're
a terrorist nation so but they may try
and unleash some terrorist attack on
some part of India inside India we have
to be careful about that so if as long
as we do these things we'll be
fine Vishna says how to deal with the
fake news peddled by our own Indian
media. We're seeing a lot of that. There
are certain Indian media outlets that
want to take the cause the side of
Pakistan. A certain media outlet uh said
that three Indian planes are confirmed
down, right? And then later
those individuals, I won't use the word
over here. Those individuals deleted the
tweet and then they said that uh it was
a mistake. They did not really apologize
for it. And I usually don't use u harsh
language on social media but I did use
harsh language for that particular
thing. So um yeah India has it's it's
more than its share of
antinationals and that's because they
people like these are most likely on the
payroll of outside forces.
So maybe it's time the government cracks
down on these antinationals and makes an
example of some of them. Maybe it's time
for that to
happen. Uh Narendra
Narendrai says Pakistan is making big
claims like downing five jets and three
Rafals and an unmanned drone and
probably uh a fleet of Indian UFOs also.
Yeah, this has been mentioned even by
the western media like CNN and New York
Times, probably by Pakistani journalists
because I see Muslim authors of those
posts. It's very difficult to believe
them as Pakistan is known for lying and
rarely speaking the truth. What do you
think about this? Is it true? See,
historically the western media has been
very very deeply and closely aligned
with Pakistani interests. It's a legacy
of the old cold war. It's a legacy of
the of of the time when the the US
funded and financed Pakistani terrorism
against India for decades and therefore
their media was completely aligned with
the Pakistani interest and they would
always take the side of Pakistan no
matter what happened with India. I
remember when I was a kid in the late
1980s and early 1990s the Pakistanis had
unleashed this wave of terrorism in
Jammu and Kashmir. Hundreds of terror
incidents every single day and the
Kashmir Hindus were evicted out of
Kashmir. Those who could not leave were
killed, right? And when India would uh
raise this at the United Nations or with
the US, you know what the Americans
would say to us? They would say that
this is your law and order issue and
you're not able to deal with simple law
and order matters. That's what the
Americans would repeatedly say to India
and they knew what was happening because
they were funding and financing the
terrorism done by Pakistan. The
Americans
were 2008 Mumbai attacks who was the
mastermind of the 2008 Mumbai attacks.
It was an American citizen an American
terrorist called David Coleman Headley.
He is in a US prison. India has an
extradition treaty with the Americans.
The Americans refuse to hand over David
Coleman Hedley to India, an American
terrorist. What are the Americans
hiding? They have a lot to hide because
they are the ones who taught Pakistan
how to use terror as a state as an
instrument of state policy. They are the
ones who funded and Pak financed
Pakistani terrorism against India for
decades. And because of this history,
their entire media was aligned with
Pakistan and it still is aligned to a
very large extent with Pakistan. Even
the British media is aligned with
Pakistan. Even the French media, you
know there is this one of the oldest
French publications is called Lufigo.
Let's let's Google it, shall we? Ligo.
You know who owns this this
French
publication? Let's let's let's look at
this. Let's look. This is important.
Okay. Lu
Figaro. Okay. Let's go to Okay. Uh, etc.
Wikipedia. It was founded in
1826. Who owns
Luffy? Who owns
Luffy? Um, it is owned by the Dault
Group. Who is the Dault group? What do
they
manufacture? The DALT group manufactures
the Rafal fighter plane which they sell
to
India and they are the owners of Lufi
Garo, France's oldest newspaper which
is bitterly
anti-India. Isn't this interesting my
friends? Isn't this interesting?
Lu
Figero blatantly anti-India strongly pro
Pakistan owned by Dasaw group which
makes the
Rafal very interesting very interesting
um so that's the that's the history of
the western media the very strongly pro
Pakistan and maybe India should use some
leverage over them it's high time we
start doing these things it's high time
we just stop being a nation of pushovers
if you want to do business in India, you
better be pro- India in all ways, in
every single way.
Anyhow, Migang Kasaris says, "What
geopolitical strategies and media
diplomacy tactics have enabled Pakistan
to swiftly dominate transnational media
narratives and why is India
comparatively lagging in
establishing its counter narratives
despite its global economic and
strategic influence?" Because the
western India, western media is very
strongly aligned with Pakistan for
historical reasons. And the Pakistanis
have played the game better than India.
In the west, in the US especially,
corruption is legalized. It's called
lobbying. Okay? You can give money to
politicians and media and all that if
you do it in through a process called
lobbying. So there are lobbying firms
that you hire and that's how you launder
the money and so on. And India can also
do that. But India has never done that.
India has never hired lobbying firms to
to put forth India's narrative. The
Pakistanis have been doing that for
decades. We have more money than
Pakistan but the Pakistanis do it. We
don't do it. I don't know why we don't
do it. We choose to do nothing. So
that's why the Pakistani narrative
typically is more influential than the
Indian narrative. It is high time India
starts using its geopolitical and
economic leverage over these nations. If
you want Amazon to do business in India,
then maybe the Washington Post which is
owned by the owner of Amazon should be
more strongly pro- India and entirely
anti-Pakistan. Maybe it's time that
happens. So we need to start using
leverage in this matter in this manner.
We need to isolate Pakistan entirely
economically,
diplomatically, in all other ways in
through sporting ties every way. We need
to isolate Pakistan. If McDonald's wants
to wants to operate in India, it needs
to choose between India and Pakistan.
You either operate in India and have
access to the Indian market or if you
love Pakistan market so much, you can
operate there and you can no longer
operate in India. You make a choice.
Give the same choice to Coca-Cola, to
Pepsi, to Domino's, to KFC, to every
American and
Western company that wants to operate in
India. Give everybody the same choice.
Choose India or Pakistan. You can't have
both,
right? Tell every cricket uh playing
country to make a choice. If you want to
play against Pakistan, if you want your
players to play the Pakistan Premier
League or whatever it is called, please
feel free to do that. But you can't do
that with you can't play with India
again and so on. It's so easy to
completely isolate Pakistan, the
terrorist nation, if we want to. So
don't you think my friends it's high
time that happens? Please pressurize the
Indian government to do the right thing.
Maybe they're not aware of it. Maybe the
there there's a lot of things that they
have in their minds. So maybe we should
put this in front of them and tell them
that we have this option and we should
use this
option. Okay. Uh Chiagraasti says with
the use of AI enabled drone swarms,
Israeli Harop loitering munitions and
real-time coordination with air defense
systems like the S400 is India now
entering a phase of integrated network
ccentric warfare. What structural,
doctrinal and logistical transformations
must India undertake to institutionalize
such a capability across the border
armed force broader armed forces beyond
episodic operations like Synindur? you
know uh yeah you can see that there is
more networks network ccentricness in
India's warfare now so we have uh
loitering drones which collect
information in real time signals
intelligence other visual intelligence
and so on yeah uh we have medium
altitude long endurance male drones or
hail drones which which will loiter for
days if required which will be doing
this reconnaissance and u intelligence
gathering then you'll have these killer
drones which are also loiterers like the
herob drone which will beworked with the
bigger ones with the hail or male
drones. Then you have the S400 which may
or may not be talking to these systems.
Then you may have fighter planes which
areorked or may not beworked. Then you
have AI enabled drone swarms which are
other drones which do the things. So all
of this if you can network it together
it creates an entire in integrated
synthesized view of the battle space
that no one person or one fighter plane
can see you know and you can integrate
this in real time through satellites and
whatn not but for that all your systems
need to be able to talk to each other
but if you have an S400 which can't talk
to a Rafal then it kind of creates gaps
so what so we are kind of going in that
direction clearly network ccentric
warfare integrated networkcentric
warfare. But for that to happen
properly, we need to manufacture all our
own
equipment. So that's what needs to
happen eventually. We we will go get
there
eventually. Arana says, "Does Pakistan
really want a small scale war with
India? Why is the US and West not
imposing sanctions on Pakistan for
harboring terrorism on soil? The West
doesn't want to talk about Pakistani
terrorism
anymore. No, no, no. We will not we we
we want to wash our hands off Pakistan.
Wash off. Let them go to China. That's
what the West is doing right now. That's
what Donald Trump is actively doing. He
has washed his hands of Pakistan. He's
okay with Pakistan falling into the
Chinese embrace. And the West doesn't
want to talk about Pakistani
terrorism. Donald Trump wants to say
that India and Pakistan has have been
fighting for 1,500 years apparently.
So why is the west so reluctant to talk
about Pakistan terrorism and all that?
Because the west funded and financed
Pakistani terrorism for decades against
India, the US. So that's why it's a very
inconvenient part of history for the US
and they want India on their side right
now. So I think so that's why they
they're keeping their hands off the
matter and Pakistan now is kind of on
its own unless China comes to the
rescue. Hersha says could Turkeykey's
consistent support for Pakistan a rogue
nation teetering on the edge of failure
be driven by deeper strategic ambitions
such as gaining access to nuclear
technology that might eventually shift
the balance of power to central Europe
in central Europe. Could such a move
serve Turkeykey's broader geopolitical
interests in Erdogan's aspiration of
reviving the Ottoman Empire or something
like that a neo-toman empire look there
are multiple reasons why Turkey and
Pakistan have this synergy or whatever
it is the Turk the first of all the
Pakistanis how do they define Pakistan
as a nation or how do they define being
a Pakistani what is what does it mean to
be a Pakistani according to Pakistan
being a Pakistani means be means means
not being Indian. They define themselves
by what they are
not. Look 80 years ago they were all
Indians right their ancestors were
Indians for tens of thousands of years
but today they have chosen not to be
Indians so they they reject being
Indians and that's why they are looking
for new new sources of ancestry or
whatever. So for some for for many years
they they tried to they pretended to be
Arabs the Pakistanis but the Arabs don't
like them. So the Arabs now say get lost
you are not Arabs you're Hindus for
Arabs Hindus means a geographical region
India. So then now the Pakistanis are
trying to become Turks. So our ancestors
were Turks. I think Immran Khan even
said that once as the prime minister of
Pakistan that the Turks ruled India for
a thousand years and that's that's our
ancestors. They're not even Turks
actually you know even the Turks
themselves are Greeks. So but anyhow
there's this the Pakistan Pakistanis
need some kind of fake ancestry so they
look towards Turkey for that and of
course there's the religious connection
the Sunni Islam thing in both nations.
So and and obviously Turkey would not
mind uh tapping into a little bit of the
nuclear technology that Pakistan has.
They know that Pakistan is a mercenary
nation. They are available at the right
price. So makes sense for this these two
nations to work together and Turkey it's
history you know Turkey doesn't have a
history. Turkey doesn't have a history.
Turkey has a criminal record.
So very similar nations, you know. So
that's
why it's it's
not it's not surprising to see
Turkeykey's consistent support for
Pakistan. Adi says if Aim Moner again
makes a stupid move and attacks India in
response to whatever happened. We
clearly said it's a non-escalatory
action and attack attacked only the
terrorist camps in Pakistan. So if Aim
Mon does something stupid, will that be
the perfect opportunity to take back
some land of PK? Actually yes pulse
pause war if push comes to shove we
pulse we pulse 20 30 km forwards if
required 50 km maximum 72 hours and then
unilateral pause end that's it we
defeated you p great choice take
muzafarabad take whatever it may happen
in the next couple of weeks or maybe the
next 3 4 days if the Pakistanisu are
stupid so some part of PK may come back
to India very very rapidly. Be prepared
for that. It may
happen. Vun Kumar says, "How far is this
going to escalate? It doesn't look like
this has ended yet. It's just phase one.
What would or should be India's end goal
here?" It's ongoing. I I came into this
room 2 hours ago. I saw on TV the
Pakistanis were trying to target Jammu.
They were trying to strike at Jammu with
missiles and drones. So, it's ongoing.
They are choosing
to attempt
escalation. They have essentially no
choice because if they don't do it then
the Pakistan army loses all legitimacy
and credibility in the eyes of its own
people. And that is do or die for
aim. So we are in a state of war with
Pakistan. Now it may not be a war that's
been declared by the two nations but we
are at war with Pakistan. And this may
last two days, it may last two weeks.
The longer it lasts, the more dangerous
it gets for Pakistan and the closer
Pakistan gets to disintegrating. Just
two weeks Pakistan can disintegrate if
it continues like this. And India's end
goal should be to impose a
comprehensive military and political
defeat on Pakistan and ensure that
Pakistan terrorism never raises its
head, snake head again. That's the end
goal.
Uh Adar Narayan Ra says as an ordinary
citizen of parat what's our duty now in
this situation that we are at war of
Pakistan how can we help or contribute
to our country in the situation number
one don't panic number
two you must support your nation
unconditionally that's all nothing else
is required of ordinary citizens
absolutely nothing else you don't have
to contribute money to the nation you
are paying taxes that's The government
has more than enough money. There is no
shortage of anything in India. The armed
forces have enough people. They have
everything they need. The only thing you
need to do as citizens is to give your
unconditional support to the country.
That's it. No questions asked. You
always support your country no matter
what happens. And don't uh amplify
rumors on social media and don't indulge
in any kind of
negativity. Unconditional support your
country. That's all that's required. All
right, I'm out of questions. Let me take
questions from the live chat for about 5
minutes. Okay, do we have
questions? Um, Pawan says Pakistan has
lost more than three fighter planes and
India has now launched 100 missiles on
Pakistan. Now, is this happening in real
time? I am I am not watching TV right
now, so I have no idea. Is this
happening right now? Um, I don't know.
Let's see. I'll I'll reassess once this
live stream is over, but okay. It's It's
pretty likely that this has happened.
Any possibility of World War II? Says
Ari, no. No possibility of World War II
unless China wants to get involved. Even
in that case, it would not be World War
II. Shashad Saha says, "Is it better to
deescalate now or is it better to
flatten Pakistan now? As they have
started to fight back now, we had we not
given a proper disproportionate
response. Uh if that if they're trying
to fight back now, we can fight back
twice as hard. Our response should be
proportional slightly harder than the
Pakistani response and uh the objective
is to tell them that if you continue
this you're going to end up in a very
bad state. Uh deescalate. No we will not
deescalate. We have had enough of being
the
deescalator. We have had enough of
deescalating. We have done decades of
that. It is time that the Pakistanis
deescalate and we will make them de
deescalate by speaking to them in the
only language they
understand. Okay. What
next? Vidan says World War II has been
initiated apparently. Okay. I am not
aware of what's happened in the past two
hours. I'll go and check once I'm done
with this. Um Rajigan says if so will
the Pakistanis use the F-16 for attacks
and cross into Indian airspace and how
will the US react? The US apparently has
kill switches which they can ensure
which they can use to ensure the
Pakistanis don't use the F-16 against
India. The reason the Pakistanis have
the F-16 is because the Americans told
them that we are selling it to you so
that you can fight
terrorism. But obviously everyone the
whole universe including
extraterrestrials they know that this is
a lie. The only reason the Pakistanis
have the F-16 is to use against India.
So look if the Pakistanis use the F-16
we need to destroy them all. That's the
simplest thing I can say and we have the
capability to do that. If they use it,
we destroy it. End of story. And if they
use it, we destroy the air bases too.
Try it. Come on. Swami says war is live.
All right. I I said two hours ago we are
in a state of
war. Uh K4 whatever says what will
happen on the Bangladesh and Sri Lanka
border? Nothing. Nothing. Nothing. It's
all right. Nothing will happen there.
Um okay they have attacked the Jammu
airport just now uh right after the
night after Sundur 2.0. Okay so this is
realtime news that I that you all are
giving me and I appreciate that. So once
this is done we're going to I'm going to
take a look at what's happening.
Pakistani J7 was shot down the Pakist
the cap the pilot was captured alive.
All right. Indian army is in Pakistan.
All right. It looks like we have a lot
of breaking news happening. So I think
I'll end the live stream right now. Um,
Subraat says, "Watched India utilize
more than 50 drones of Pakistan in
Udampur. I am surprised I were able to
reach reach Udampur. What's my take on
this?" Uh, I don't know what to say. I
have to see what happened and we'll see.
Okay. So, uh, Misty 88 says, "Will we
have the regular Saturday night ask a
visit session?" Yes. Yes, we're going to
have that. So, we will continue this
this conversation on Saturday. Let me
end today's live stream over here. Thank
you so much for your questions,
viewership, and everything. And let's do
this, let's continue this on Saturday.
Until then, take care and thank you very
very much for questions. Stay safe and
keep supporting your nation
unconditionally. Thank you, Jind. I'll
see you soon.